(upbeat music)
- Hello, English learners.
Welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And we're gonna be looking at our
fifth episode of our famous love story.
- Yes, I'm sorry, I love you.
- Okay.
- Part five.
So if you haven't listened
to the first four, I suggest you
go do that first, because
you're gonna be a little bit lost,
but it's getting really good.
- Yeah, and so, so good that I don't think
we can even say what's gonna happen next.
- I can't sit with the key languages.
- Oh.
- Yeah, we can't preview anything
because it's, we want to surprise you.
- Yes.
- But we can tell you
this, what's going on?
- The last time we saw Veronica
and Stephen, they broke up, right?
- Right.
- And Veronica was with her
friend and feeling really terrible,
and then Stephen suddenly
came to sing a beautiful song.
- So this is continuing on that.
- Right.
- Okay, so let's listen to the dialogue,
and then we'll come back and talk about
some of the difficult
vocabulary we might find.
(upbeat music)
- Honey, of course I forgive you.
I love you so much.
I've really missed you.
I was wrong to get upset over nothing.
- I'm sorry I haven't called or anything,
but right after you decided
you wanted to break,
I was up north to put out
some major forest fires.
I was in the middle of
nowhere, working day and
night, trying to prevent
the blaze from spreading.
It was pretty intense.
- Oh honey, I'm glad you're okay,
but I have some exciting news.
I think I'm pregnant.
- Really?
- Wow, that's amazing.
This is great news.
I've always wanted to be a father.
We'll go to the doctor
first thing in the morning.
(upbeat music)
(water splashing)
- We have your test results back,
and indeed, you are pregnant.
Let's see here.
Everything seems to be an order.
Your approximate due
date is October 27th, 2009,
so that means the baby was
conceived on February 3rd, 2009.
Are you sure?
Are these things accurate?
- Well, yes sir, they are.
- What's wrong?
Why are you asking these questions?
- This baby is in mind.
I was away the first week of
February at training seminar.
- I, I, no, it can't be.
(upbeat music)
- All right, so more
drama in our love story.
- Oh my God.
- Things were going well,
and now more bad news.
- Yeah, or good news.
- Oh, good news.
- We're not sure yet.
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's take a look at the
vocabulary first in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- Well, we're gonna look at four words now.
The first one, glaze, glaze, glaze.
So this noun is another
word for a fire, right?
- We're a big fire.
- Yeah, a really big fire.
- The blaze.
So basically it's like
the flame of the fire.
- Yes, this one is a little bit difficult.
So I think we can use some examples
to show us how to use this word.
- Example one.
- The blaze is spreading quickly.
We need to evacuate these people.
- Example two.
- We have to go in there and
save those people from the blaze.
- Okay, so it's clear now, blaze.
Let's look at our next word, conceived.
- Conceived.
- The past of conceive.
- Right, conceived.
- Conceived is a nice fancy word.
- Yes, and what does it mean, Marco?
- To create.
- Oh, like how your side stepped around.
- So it means to create.
You can conceive a baby.
- Yes. - You can conceive an idea.
- Yes.
- So it basically means to create.
- Yes, most commonly with the baby.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, conceived.
So after the baby was conceived.
- Yep.
- We have a due date.
- Yes.
- We all know that it's nine
months later, approximately.
- Yep, due dates.
- So the due date is the
date of birth, basically.
- It's the doctor's guess
when the birth would be.
- Would be, okay.
- When you go to the doctor and
say, "When will my baby be born?"
He'll say, "Well, your due
date is blah, blah, blah.
" - Nine months later.
- Yep.
- Okay.
And our last word in
language takeaway, accurate.
- Accurate.
- Now, the due dates aren't accurate.
- Right.
- That means they're
not 100% sure or precise.
- Yes.
- So when something is
accurate, it's absolutely certain.
- Absolutely precise.
- Yes.
- 100%.
Okay, so accurate, let's listen to some
more examples of how we can use accurate.
- Example one.
- A blood test is the most accurate way
of finding out if you're pregnant.
- Example two.
- These reports are not accurate, John.
We checked and
discovered a lot of mistakes.
- Example three.
- This new software helps us
calculate costs in a very accurate way.
- With those examples, I think we're
ready to listen to this dialogue again.
This time we're gonna slow it down, right?
- Yeah, in case you were so shocked by
what happened that you couldn't follow.
Honey, of course I forgive
you, I love you so much.
I've really missed you.
Please forgive me, I was
wrong to get upset over nothing.
- I'm sorry I haven't called or anything,
but right after you decided
you wanted to break,
I was called up north to put
out some major forest fires.
I was in the middle of
nowhere, working day and night,
trying to prevent the blaze from spreading.
It was pretty intense.
- Oh honey, I'm glad you're okay,
but I have some exciting news.
I think I'm pregnant.
- Really?
Wow, that's amazing.
This is create news.
I've always wanted to be a father.
We'll go to the doctor
first thing in the morning.
We have your test results back,
and indeed you are pregnant.
Let's see here.
Everything seems to be an order.
Your approximate new
date is October 27th, 2009,
so that means the baby was
conceived on February 3rd, 2009.
Are you sure?
Are these things accurate?
Well, yes sir, they are.
- What's wrong?
Why are you asking these questions?
- This baby isn't mine.
I was away the first week of
February at a training seminar.
- I, I, no, it can't be.
- All right, so continuing
on with our drama,
let's take a look at some
interesting phrases in fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
Well, we've got three phrases for you.
The first one is the middle of nowhere.
- Middle of nowhere.
- This is a kind of a funny one, but I
think if we listen to some examples,
it will help us to understand
the meaning of this phrase.
- Example one.
- We are in the middle of nowhere.
How can we find our way back home?
- Example two.
- I was in the middle of nowhere, so
I couldn't even use my mobile phone.
- Example three.
- It takes me two hours
to drive to your house.
It's in the middle of nowhere.
- All right, so middle of
nowhere it means that you are lost.
- Yeah, you're in a place with no
cities or people or anything nearby.
- Okay, so just imagine yourself in a
desert that would be the middle of nowhere.
- Yes, or in Canada.
- In Canada, that would
be the middle of nowhere.
- All right, let's take a
look at our next phrase.
First thing in the morning.
- First thing in the morning.
- So when we talk about the first thing,
it means really, really
early in the morning.
- Really early.
- So I can change it a little bit
and say first thing in the afternoon.
- Early in the afternoon.
- Or first thing tomorrow morning.
- Right.
- So really early tomorrow.
- Okay, so it's a very common
way of referring to very early.
- Yeah, it's not like first
thing in the morning
is like six o'clock in
the morning, right?
But if you say, okay, I'll
take care of that first thing
in the morning, you'll do it
right away in the morning.
- Right away.
Right when you get to
the office, for example.
- Yeah.
- Okay, let's look at our last phrase.
Seems to be in order.
- Seems to be in order.
- Everything seems to be in order.
- So everything is okay,
everything's normal.
- Everything seems to be normal.
Everything looks okay.
- Yes.
- So this is a very common phrase
when people check your documents
or reports, they'll say, okay, all
the papers seem to be in order.
Very common.
- Yes, good news when you're pregnant
that everything seems to be in order.
- Exactly, yeah.
- Everything is normal, all right.
So let's listen to this
dramatic dialogue one
more time and we'll
come back and talk to you.
(upbeat music)
- Honey, of course I forgive you.
I love you so much, I've really missed you.
I was wrong to get upset over nothing.
I'm sorry I haven't called or anything,
but right after you decided
you wanted to break,
I was up north to put out
some major forest fires.
I was in the middle of nowhere working day
and I had tried to prevent
the blaze from spreading.
It was pretty intense.
- Oh honey, I'm glad you're okay,
but I have some exciting news.
I think I'm pregnant.
- Really?
- Wow, that's amazing, this is great news.
I've always wanted to be a father.
We'll go to the doctor
first thing in the morning.
(upbeat music)
We have your test results back
and indeed you are pregnant.
Let's see here, everything
seems to be an order.
Your approximate due
date is October 27th, 2009.
So that means the baby was
conceived on February 3rd, 2009.
Are you sure?
Are these things accurate?
- Well, yes sir, they are.
- What's wrong?
Why are you asking these questions?
- This baby is in mind.
I was away the first week of
February at training seminar.
- I, I, no, it can't be.
(upbeat music)
- Well, Marco, what do you
think about this situation?
What would you do if you were this guy?
- It's complicated.
- I know.
- I don't know what I would do.
It seems like something
very typical of soap operas.
- Yes.
- Well, I don't know
because she didn't really
deny it in the end, she
didn't say no right away.
- Yeah, and, but she didn't say like, oh.
- Yeah, she didn't really accept it.
So it's still a little bit difficult to see
if maybe she cheated on him or something.
- Hey guys, what do you think?
Do you think Veronica cheated on Stephen?
- Do you think it's his baby?
Maybe it's not.
Maybe the doctor is wrong.
- Maybe it's the doctor's baby.
- Maybe it's anything could
happen here at English Pod.
So send us your ideas and tell us,
what do you think happens next?
Come to EnglishPod.com where you
can leave your questions, your comments.
- Yeah, and Mark and I are always around
to answer your questions,
respond to your comments.
- Exactly, and we want to know
what you think will happen next.
- Yes.
- All right guys, so until next time.
- Bye. - Bye.
(upbeat music)